Guide to the Maria Mitchell Papers, 1843-2016 (bulk 1853-1889)
Vassar College Libraries Archives and Special Collections
- SERIES X. GLASS PLATE NEGATIVES, 1871-1890
  - Sunspots, observed by Arnold and Stow, 1873 Dec 15 (Neg. Box 3)
    Notes: "One group of small spots"
  - Sunspots, observed by [unknown], circa 1874 (Neg. Box 36.3)
  - Sunspots, observed by Arnold and Stow, 1874 Jan 10 (Neg. Box 27)
    Notes: "Two small groups, one very small single spot."
  - Sunspots, observed by Arnold and Stow, 1874 Jan 19 12:07 PM (Neg. Box 27)
    Notes: "Angle of Diurnal motion 1º. Several small spots near eastern limb. Three small ones near western"
  - Sunspots, observed by Arnold and Stow, 1874 Jan 20 12:06 PM (Neg. Box 27)
    Notes: "Angle of Diurnal motion 1º. One good-sized spot, two smaller ones"
  - Sunspots, observed by Arnold and Stow, 1874 Jan 24 12:41 PM (Neg. Box 27)
    Notes: "Pair of spots just within eastern limb, one approaching the center, one near western limb"
  - Sunspots, observed by Arnold and Stow, 1874 Jan 26 12:19 PM (Neg. Box 27)
    Notes: "Angle of diurnal motion 2º. Five row of spots."
  - Sunspots, observed by Arnold and Stow, 1874 Jan 29 12:31 PM (Neg. Box 27)
    Notes: "A supplementary to this shows the missing part. In this are five good-sized spots, one of which or rather the pair, was seen thro' smoked glass by the naked eye."
  - Sunspots, observed by [unknown], 1874 Jan 29 (Neg. Box 27)
    Notes: "Supplementary to another picture taken on same day a part of which was accidentally cut off by the failure of the acid to sensitize the whole plate. The section given in this contains the part lacking in the other and shows two small sots just within the eastern limb."
  - Sunspots, observed by Stow and Arnold, 1874 Jan 30 12:12 PM (Neg. Box 27)
    Notes: "Angle 4º"
  - Sunspots, observed by Arnold and Stow, 1874 Feb 5 12:50 PM (Neg. Box 27)
    Notes: "Two near western limb separated by a diameter from two near eastern limb"
  - Sunspots, observed by Arnold and Stow, 1874 Feb 10 12:48 PM (Neg. Box 27)
    Notes: "Angle of Motion 4º. One spot near center, two small ones coming on."
  - Sunspots, observed by Arnold and Stow, 1874 Feb 12 12:23 PM (Neg. Box 28)
    Notes: "angle. 4º Three small spots, the same as those of yesterday"
  - Sunspots, observed by Arnold and Stow, 1874 Feb 14 12:16 PM (Neg. Box 28)
    Notes: "Six small spots nearly in the horizontal diameter (the western spot of the pair should appear as two.)"
  - Sunspots, observed by Arnold and Stow, 1874 Feb 17 12:15 PM (Neg. Box 28)
    Notes: "One large spot coming on, two very small near the center; faculae."
  - Sunspots, observed by Stow and Arnold, 1874 Feb 18 [12:31 PM?] (Neg. Box 28)
    Notes: "Two small spots have disappeared; one small new spot appeared near center, and some larger is just coming on. Faculae."
  - Sunspots, observed by Arnold and Stow, 1874 Feb 20 12:17 PM (Neg. Box 28)
    Notes: "Several small spots; faculae."
  - Sunspots, observed by Arnold and “Maggie”, 1874 Feb 26 (Neg. Box 28)
    Notes: "One spot just coming on a group further on, near this a circular spot, another circular spot on the other side of the center."
  - Sunspots, observed by Arnold and Stow, 1874 Feb 28 (Neg. Box 28)
    Notes: "One large sot with palm-shaped umbra; several small ones."
  - Sunspots, observed by Arnold and Stow, 1874 Mar 2 12:18 PM (Neg. Box 15)
    Notes: "Decided changes since the last picture was taken (Feb. 28). One group of small ones, a pair quite large. The small ones on a line from the pair to the western limb. The large pair seems to have moved measurably [unusually?] since Feb. 28."
  - Sunspots, observed by Stow and Arnold, 1874 Mar 2 (Neg. Box 27)
    Notes: "Duplicate. Two small groups above and west of center"
  - Sunspots, observed by Arnold and Stow, 1874 Mar 3 (Neg. Box 10)
    Notes: "Three spots near western limb, two just within eastern limb, is this not an unusual degree of change of position in the former since yesterday?"
  - Sunspots, observed by Arnold and Stow, 1874 Mar 4 12:02 PM (Neg. Box 15)
    Notes: "One large group going off two small groups, one below center, one coming on, also two single spots near eastern limb which are not visible. Picture taken 11 minutes after."
  - Sunspots, observed by Arnold and Stow, 1874 Mar 4 [12:13 PM?] (Neg. Box 27)
    Notes: "Compare this with one taken 11 minutes before, Two spots visible in the latter appeared in the interval, otherwise there is no change."
  - Sunspots, observed by Arnold and Stow, 1874 Mar 5 12:11 PM (Neg. Box 35)
    Notes: "Spots much the same as yesterday but showing some slight changes. Large group still on, small group coming on, faculae."
  - Sunspots, observed by Stow and Fisher, 1874 Mar 1412:16 PM (Neg. Box 35)
    Notes: "Duplicate. Spots large"
  - Sunspots, observed by Stow and Fisher, 1874 Mar 1412:47 PM (Neg. Box 35)
    Notes: "Spots very large. Nearly in line of horizontal axis. Prof. Mitchell"
  - Sunspots, observed by Stow and Cutter, 1874 Mar 2112:44 PM (Neg. Box 27)
    Notes: "One spot just going off, one group near center; faculae."
  - Sunspots, observed by Arnold and Fisher, 1874 Mar 2512:15 PM (Neg. Box 27)
    Notes: "Pair of small spots near center; ditto near western limb; small spot near eastern limb; faculae."
  - Sunspots, observed by Arnold and Cutter, 1874 Mar 2712:27 PM (Neg. Box 28)
    Notes: "Total change of spots since Mar. 25. one group, two single spots. Faculae."
  - Sunspots, observed by Arnold and Gardner, 1874 Mar 28 (Neg. Box 27)
    Notes: "Changes from March 27 to March 28 are very peculiar, Pair of spots near western limb; single spot above center."
  - Sunspots, observed by Arnold and Cutter, 1874 Mar 30 12:29 PM (Neg. Box 28)
    Notes: "Very large spot (in group) just within eastern limb, group near western limb, single well defined spot to the right above center; faculae. (The printed pictures marked 1 to 8 follow this negative)? Two of these negatives, (--) have been returned from --. But some half dozen negatives following this date have not been found."
  - Sunspots, observed by Arnold and Gardner, 1874 Apr 2 1:20 PM?] (Neg. Box 7)
    Notes: "Spots not well defined; good sized pair coming on (i.e.. East of center);"
  - Sunspots, observed by Arnold and Gardner, 1874 Apr 3 [1:23 PM?] (Neg. Box 7)
    Notes: "Spots the same as yesterday; not well defined; faculae."
  - Sunspots, observed by Arnold and Stow, 1874 Apr 18 12:37 PM (Neg. Box 27)
    Notes: "Small pair above center; faculae."
  - Sunspots, observed by Stow and Arnold, 1874 Apr 27 12:31 PM (Neg. Box 27)
    Notes: "One large spot coming on. Faculae near spot. Small spot above and right of center."
  - Sunspots, observed by Arnold and Stow, 1874 Apr 30 2:16 PM (Neg. Box 27)
    Notes: "Poorly defined; small group to the right, single spot to left of center."
  - Sunspots, observed by Arnold and Stow, 1874 May 1 12:00 PM (Neg. Box 9)
    Notes: "Pair of very small spots just within eastern limb. Single spot east of center, group of small ones west of center, definition very poor."
  - Sunspots, observed by Barton and Gardner, 1874 May 3 (Neg. Box 9)
    Notes: "Same groups"
  - Sunspots, observed by Arnold and [unknown], 1874 May 6 11:23 AM; [plate broken] (Neg. Box 9)
    Notes: "3 groups; one near eastern limb, one near center, one near western limb."
  - Sunspots, observed by Arnold and Stow, 1874 May 7 (Neg. Box 7)
    Notes: "Triplicate. Four groups. Spots large and numerous."
  - Sunspots, observed by Arnold and Stow, 1874 May 7 (Neg. Box 9)
  - Sunspots, observed by Arnold and Stow, 1874 May 9 2:17 PM (Neg. Box 9)
    Notes: "Two fine groups east of center; two pairs near western limb."
  - Sunspots, observed by Arnold and Gardner, 1874 May 10 12:43 PM (Neg. Box 7)
    Notes: "Two groups nearing the center; spots also near western limb one group surrounded by conspicuous faculae; faculae also near eastern limb. May 11th and 12th, no spots visible - plates destroyed each."
  - Sunspots, observed by Stow and Arnold, 1874 May 13 12:32 PM (Neg. Box 7)
    Notes: "one large group near the center and two spots to the right of the group. 'Mottled surface' very strongly marked."
  - Sunspots, observed by Arnold and Cushing, 1874 May 14 12:17 PM (Neg. Box 7)
    Notes: "Large group east of and below center; pair of spots above and to the right of group."
  - Sunspots, observed by Arnold and Cushing, 1874 May 15 12:12 PM (Neg. Box 7)
    Notes: "Large group near western limb; pair of very small spots to the right and above the group; faculae"
  - Sunspots, observed by Arnold and Cushing, 1874 May 17 (Neg. Box 9)
    Notes: "Small spot coming on, group going off (this has been visible since May 7)"
  - Sunspots, observed by Arnold and Stow, 1874 May 19 12:43 PM (Neg. Box 27)
    Notes: "Two groups east of center, single spot near eastern limb, another near western limb. Spots all very small; faculae."
  - Sunspots, observed by Stow and Arnold, 1874 May 21 1:59 PM?] (Neg. Box 27)
    Notes: "One group east of center and below it"
  - Sunspots, observed by Stow and Cushing, 1874 May 23 1:28 PM (Neg. Box 9)
    Notes: "Group to the right and below the center"
  - Sunspots, observed by Arnold and Cushing, 1874 May 27 12:45 PM (Neg. Box 9)
    Notes: "Good sized group near eastern limb (duplicate, preserved on account of remarkable distinctness of faculae; the “mottled surface” can also be well distinguished)"
  - Sunspots, observed by Stow and Arnold, 1874 May 27 12:29 PM (Neg. Box 9)
    Notes: "Good-sized group near eastern limb, extensive faculae."
  - Sunspots, observed by Arnold and Cushing, 1874 May 28 12:23 PM (Neg. Box 9)
    Notes: "Good sized group above and to the left of the center; faculae"
  - Sunspots, observed by Cushing and Stow, 1874 May 29 12:15 PM (Neg. Box 9)
    Notes: "One good-sized group above he center and a little to the left"
  - Sunspots, observed by Arnold and Cushing, 1874 May 30 12:25 PM (Neg. Box 27)
    Notes: "Same group as yesterday (good sized and above the center). Faculae."
  - Sunspots, observed by Stow and Cushing, 1874 Jun 1 12:20 PM (Neg. Box 9)
    Notes: "One group to the right of he center, single spot near eastern limb. Spots good-sized."
  - Sunspots, observed by Arnold and Cushing, 1874 Jun 8 12:20 PM (Neg. Box 9)
    Notes: "Three small spots east of the center, two pairs of small spots west of center (one pair very near western limb) faculae"
  - Sunspots, observed by Arnold and Cushing, 1874 Jun 9 12:27 PM (Neg. Box 9)
    Notes: "Duplicate not valuable; the other picture is not so good chemically but defines the spots better"
  - Sunspots, observed by Arnold and Cushing, 1874 Jun 10 12:19 PM (Neg. Box 27)
    Notes: "Two groups of small spots near the center; faculae. Marked change since June 1"
  - Sunspots, observed by Cushing and Stow, 1874 Jun 13 12:40 PM (Neg. Box 27)
    Notes: "Spot just appearing within eastern limb, four small spots west of center."
  - Sunspots, observed by Stow and Cushing, 1874 Jun 15 12:25 PM (Neg. Box 27)
    Notes: "Large group, with faculae, near eastern limb; three small spots west of center; faculae near western limb."
  - Sunspots, observed by Stow and Barton, 1874 Jun 18 1:12 PM (Neg. Box 36.4)
    Notes: "Two good-sized groups. Faculae."
  - Sunspots, observed by Arnold and Gardner, 1874 Jun 21 12:48 PM (Neg. Box 9)
    Notes: "Same group, faculae"
  - Sunspots, observed by Arnold and Lupton, 1874 Jun 23 11:36 AM (Neg. Box 36.15)
    Notes: "Same large group, faculae"
  - Sunspots, observed by Arnold and Gardner, 1874 Sep 26 12:19 PM (Neg. Box 35)
    Notes: "One large spot."
  - Sunspots, observed by Barton and Gardner, 1874 Oct 3 12:02 PM (Neg. Box 35)
    Notes: "Large group of spots"
  - Sunspots, observed by Barton and Gardner, 1874 Oct 3 12:01 PM (Neg. Box 35)
  - Sunspots, observed by Gardner and Metcalf, 1874 Oct 4 (Neg. Box 35)
    Notes: "A regular motion of the group of spots. (there are some very faint notes concerning Oct. 5 under this note that are very faint and hard to read. Something about groups appearing near the edge, etc.)"
  - Sunspots, observed by Barton and Gardner, 1874 Oct 5 12:01 PM (Neg. Box 35)
    Notes: "Same large group "
  - Sunspots, observed by Arnold and Stow, 1874 Oct 9 12:05 PM (Neg. Box 3)
    Notes: "3°. 5. Poor focus; spots few."
  - Sunspots, observed by Barton and Gardner, 1874 Oct 9 12:30 PM (Neg. Box 35)
    Notes: "Large group with faculae going off, two small groups"
  - Sunspots, observed by Barton and Gardner, 1874 Oct 12 12:45 PM (Neg. Box 35)
    Notes: "Two spots, going off."
  - Sunspots, observed by Barton and Gardner, 1874 Oct 15 12:05 PM (Neg. Box 35)
    Notes: "Small group, spot coming on"
  - Sunspots, observed by Barton and Gardner, 1874 Oct 16 12:15 PM (Neg. Box 35)
    Notes: "Two small groups "
  - Sunspots, observed by Barton and Gardner, 1874 Oct 17 [2:15 PM?] (Neg. Box 35)
    Notes: "Same spots with another to the east and lower."
  - Sunspots, observed by Barton and Gardner, 1874 Oct 19 (Neg. Box 35)
    Notes: "Same spots as on the 17th picture imperfect."
  - Sunspots, observed by Barton and Gardner, 1874 Oct 20 (Neg. Box 35)
    Notes: "Same spots with another near the center not visible yesterday."
  - Sunspots, observed by Barton and Gardner, 1874 Oct 22 (Neg. Box 35)
    Notes: "The spot which appeared near center on [Oct 20] has disappeared and also the most westerly of the other three."
  - Sunspots, observed by Barton and Gardner, 1874 Oct 23 (Neg. Box 35)
    Notes: "Same five spots – good picture."
  - Sunspots, observed by Barton and Gardner, 1874 Oct 24 (Neg. Box 35)
    Notes: "Only one spot, another having disappeared since yesterday."
  - Sunspots, observed by Barton and Gardner, 1874 Oct 27 (Neg. Box 35)
    Notes: "Small spot with faculae near eastern limb and another near western. Faculae of eastern limb well shown."
  - Sunspots, observed by Barton and Gardner, 1874 Oct 31 (Neg. Box 35)
    Notes: "Two large spots just within eastern limb."
  - Sunspots, observed by Barton and Gardner, 1874 Nov 10 (Neg. Box 35)
    Notes: "Same large group near western limb – five or six spots."
  - Sunspots, observed by Barton and Gardner, 1874 Nov 12 (Neg. Box 35)
    Notes: "One small spot near eastern limb."
  - Sunspots, observed by Barton and Gardner, 1874 Nov 14 (Neg. Box 35)
    Notes: "Two groups of very small spots"
  - Sunspots, observed by Barton and Gardner, 1874 Nov 16 (Neg. Box 35)
    Notes: "Same two groups of small spots"
  - Sunspots, observed by Barton and Gardner, 1874 Nov 19 (Neg. Box 35)
    Notes: "One large spot and small group poorly defined."
  - Sunspots, observed by Barton and Gardner, 1874 Nov 23 (Neg. Box 35)
    Notes: "One large and one small spot. Obstruction in tube."
  - Sunspots, observed by Barton and Gardner, 1874 Nov 26 (Neg. Box 35)
    Notes: "Same spots and same trouble in tube."
  - Sunspots, observed by Barton and Gardner, 1874 Dec 4 (Neg. Box 35)
    Notes: "Two very small spots."
  - Sunspots, observed by Barton and Gardner, 1874 Dec 8 (Neg. Box 35)
    Notes: "Several very small spots. Not a good picture."
  - Sunspots, observed by Barton and Gardner, 1874 Dec 10 (Neg. Box 35)
    Notes: "Group of three large spots coming on. (Poor Picture)."
  - Sunspots, observed by Barton and Gardner, 1874 Dec 11 (Neg. Box 15)
    Notes: "Same group of three."
  - Sunspots, observed by Barton and Gardner, 1874 Dec 12 (Neg. Box 35)
    Notes: "Same three spots – the middle one double and the foremost one nearly surrounded by small ones."
  - Sunspots, observed by Barton and Gardner, 1874 Dec 15 (Neg. Box 34)
    Notes: "Same group with marked change since [Dec 12]"
  - Sunspots, observed by Barton and Gardner, 1874 Dec 16 (Neg. Box 19)
    Notes: "Same group as yesterday."
  - Sunspots, observed by Barton and Gardner, 1875 Jan 24 (Neg. Box 7)
    Notes: "Two spots western limb; (poor chemicals)"
  - Sunspots, observed by Barton and Gardner, 1875 Feb 1 (Neg. Box 7)
    Notes: "Two spots high on eastern limb. good picture."
  - Sunspots, observed by Barton and Gardner, 1875 Feb 4 (Neg. Box 7)
    Notes: "Two small spots."
  - Sunspots, observed by Barton and Gardner, 1875 Feb 5 (Neg. Box 7)
    Notes: "Same small group good picture. - Feb 10th no spots (negative destroyed)."
  - Sunspots, observed by Barton and Gardner, 1875 Feb 18 (Neg. Box 7)
    Notes: "A large spot coming on high just within the edge."
  - Sunspots, observed by Barton and Gardner, 1875 Feb 21 (Neg. Box 7)
    Notes: "Duplicate—not quite as good as the other."
  - Sunspots, observed by Barton and Gardner, 1875 Feb 21 (Neg. Box 36.14)
    Notes: "Same large spot followed by very small one and below another spot of good size followed by small group. Good picture. Penumbra well defined."
  - Sunspots, observed by Barton and Gardner, 1875 Feb 22 (Neg. Box 7)
    Notes: "Same spots picture chemically very poor."
  - Sunspots, observed by Barton and Gardner, 1875 Feb 23 (Neg. Box 7)
    Notes: "Same two large spots. Not very good definition."
  - Sunspots, observed by Barton and Gardner, 1875 Feb 26 (Neg. Box 7)
    Notes: "Same spots with some changes. The largest spot now has a very small one below. The other is divided into two and is followed by one distinct spot in place of the confused group. Two spots coming on—one of them near the center."
  - Sunspots, observed by Barton and Gardner, 1875 Feb 26 (Neg. Box 7)
    Notes: "Duplicate—chemically poorer but definition of spots better."
  - Sunspots, observed by Barton and Gardner, 1875 Mar 2 (Neg. Box 7)
    Notes: "The two small spots past center."
  - Sunspots, observed by Barton and Gardner, 1875 Mar 4 (Neg. Box 8)
    Notes: "Small spots…[illegible]"
  - Sunspots, observed by Barton and Gardner, 1875 Mar 6 (Neg. Box 7)
    Notes: "Same two spots followed by small group below."
  - Sunspots, observed by Barton and Gardner, 1875 Mar 8 (Neg. Box 7)
    Notes: "Two pairs of spots within the western limb."
  - Sunspots, observed by Barton and Gardner, 1875 Mar 8 (Neg. Box 8)
    Notes: "Duplicate. Two groups within western limb."
  - Sunspots, observed by Barton and Gardner, 1875 Mar 10 (Neg. Box 8)
    Notes: "Spot coming on surrounded by faculae."
  - Sunspots, observed by Barton and Gardner, 1875 Mar 11 (Neg. Box 8)
    Notes: "Same spot followed by another"
  - Sunspots, observed by Barton and Gardner, 1875 Mar 12 (Neg. Box 8)
    Notes: "Two spots within eastern limb."
  - Sunspots, observed by Barton and Gardner, 1875 Mar 17 (Neg. Box 8)
    Notes: "Two spots near the center with a small group below. Large spot on eastern edge."
  - Sunspots, observed by Barton and Gardner, 1875 Mar 18 (Neg. Box 8)
    Notes: "Large spot within eastern limb. Small ones west of center."
  - Sunspots, observed by Barton and Gardner, 1875 Mar 19 (Neg. Box 8)
    Notes: "Same large spot. Poor definition."
  - Sunspots, observed by Barton and Gardner, 1875 Mar 22 (Neg. Box 7)
    Notes: "Same large spot. Group of the three small ones within western limb."
  - Sunspots, observed by Barton and Gardner, 1875 Mar 23 (Neg. Box 7)
    Notes: "Same large spot and small group."
  - Sunspots, observed by Barton and Gardner, 1875 Mar 27 (Neg. Box 8)
    Notes: "Same large spot. "
  - Sunspots, observed by Barton and Gardner, 1875 Mar 29 (Neg. Box 8)
    Notes: "The large spot just within western limb. Small group near center."
  - Sunspots, observed by Gardner and Barton, 1875 Mar 30 (Neg. Box 8)
    Notes: "Same small group."
  - Sunspots, observed by Gardner and Scott, 1875 Mar 31 (Neg. Box 8)
    Notes: "Small group near center."
  - Sunspots, observed by Gardner and Scott, 1875 Apr 1 (Neg. Box 8)
    Notes: "Same small group with spot coming on"
  - Sunspots, observed by Barton and Gardner, 1875 Apr 5 (Neg. Box 8)
    Notes: "Very small group near center."
  - Sunspots, observed by Barton and Gardner, 1875 Apr 10 (Neg. Box 8)
    Notes: "Two large spots coming on. Two small ones near center."
  - Sunspots, observed by Barton and Gardner, 1875 Apr 13 (Neg. Box 34)
    Notes: "Same three spots."
  - Sunspots, observed by Barton and Gardner, 1875 Apr 17 (Neg. Box 10)
    Notes: "Two large spots."
  - Sunspots, observed by Barton and Gardner, 1875 Apr 20 (Neg. Box 10)
    Notes: "Small group going off. (Silver bath not good)."
  - Sunspots, observed by Barton and Gardner, 1875 Apr 21 (Neg. Box 10)
    Notes: "Small group (3) going off—small spot coming on."
  - Sunspots, observed by Gardner and Barton, 1875 Apr 23 (Neg. Box 10)
  - Sunspots, observed by Barton and Woodward, 1875 Apr 29 (Neg. Box 10)
    Notes: "One large group and two small ones (good picture)"
  - Sunspots, observed by Barton and Gardner, 1875 May 2 (Neg. Box 27)
    Notes: "Same large group. Chemically not good."
  - Sunspots, observed by Barton and Gardner, 1875 Jun 2 (Neg. Box 10)
    Notes: "Two spots coming on."
  - Sunspots, observed by Barton and Gardner, 1875 Jun 4 (Neg. Box 8)
    Notes: "Two spots on the eastern limb."
  - Sunspots, observed by Gardner and Barton, 1875 Jun 5 (Neg. Box 10)
    Notes: "The same spots moving regularly across the disk."
  - Sunspots, observed by Barton and Gardner, 1875 Jun 7 (Neg. Box 10)
    Notes: "One large spot followed by a small one on the western limb."
  - Sunspots, observed by Barton and Gardner, 1875 Jun 10 (Neg. Box 10)
    Notes: "Spot going off."
  - Sunspots, observed by Barton and Gardner, 1875 Jun 11 (Neg. Box)
    Notes: "Spot on the very edge - June 12. No spots (neg. destroyed)"
  - Sunspots, observed by Gardner and Barton, 1875 Jun 16 (Neg. Box 10)
    Notes: "Two spots on Eastern limb"
  - Sunspots, observed by Barton and Gardner, 1875 Jun 17 (Neg. Box 35)
    Notes: "The two spots moving regularly."
  - Sunspots, observed by Stow and Barton, 1875 Jun 18 [1:12 PM?] (Neg. Box 9)
    Notes: "Two good sized groups. Faculae"
  - Sunspots, observed by Gardner and Metcalf, 1875 Sep 29 (Neg. Box 10)
    Notes: "A Group of spots near the center"
  - Sunspots, observed by Gardner and Metcalf, 1875 Sep 30 (Neg. Box 35)
    Notes: "A regular motion of the spots."
  - Sunspots, observed by Gardner and Metcalf, 1875 Oct 2 (Neg. Box 35)
    Notes: "A regular motion of the group."
  - Sunspots, observed by Arnold and Stow, 1875 Oct 11 12:02 PM (Neg. Box 3)
    Notes: "3°. 5. Spots few; faculae going off."
  - Sunspots, observed by Gardner and Metcalf, 1875 Oct 20 (Neg. Box 17)
    Notes: "Two elongated spots followed by two very small ones. - Oct 21 The two elongated spots appear to be – into one and the two small spots following not seen."
  - Sunspots, observed by Gardner and Metcalf, 1875 Oct 22 (Neg. Box 25)
    Notes: "A regular motion of the spot across the disk."
  - Sunspots, observed by Gardner and Metcalf, 1875 Oct 28 (Neg. Box 8)
    Notes: "This is a poor negative, but the group is large—One of the two spots has separated into two smaller ones. - [Oct 29-30] Clouds prevented observations and photographing. - Oct. 31 There are but two spots in the group. - Nov. 1. Clouds prevented observations and photographing."
  - Sunspots, observed by Gardner and Metcalf, 1875 Nov 2 (Neg. Box 8)
    Notes: "Two spots with penumbra are seen. The motion appears regular. - Nov. 3 The two spots appear to have united A small spot near the center of the disk was observed which was not seen before. - Nov. 4. The large spot very nearly off; surrounded by penumbra and the faculae again visible. The small spot appears to have separated into two. - Nov. [5-6, 8-9, 12-13]. No spots (neg. destroyed)”"
  - Sunspots, observed by Gardner and Metcalf, 1875 Nov 18 (Neg. Box 8)
    Notes: "Two spots with a very small group between"
  - Sunspots, observed by Gardner and Metcalf, 1875 Nov 22 (Neg. Box 10)
    Notes: "A group on the western limb, a group on the Eastern limb followed by a small spot and two small spots near the center."